salsalabs.com 2019-05-31

# Website Privacy Policy

#### Effective Date: May 4, 2018

Salsa Labs, Inc. (“Salsa Labs,” “we” or “us") values transparency and privacy. In this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain through our website, [www.salsalabs.com](https://www.salsalabs.com/), as well as the services available via our website (collectively, the “Site”). By accessing or using our Site, you agree that we will collect and handle personal information as described in this Policy. Your use of our Site, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Service, available at www.salsalabs.com/terms-service, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. The Salsa Labs Terms of Service are incorporated by reference into this Policy.

#### **Scope of this Policy**

This Policy applies only to information collected by Salsa Labs via the Salsa Labs Site. It does not apply to other Salsa Labs platforms or services. To review the privacy policy that applies to the Salsa Labs platform and services (an online engagement, fundraising and advocacy solution offered by Salsa Labs), click www.salsalabs.com/privacy-policy.

#### **What Information Do We Collect?**

We may collect information directly from customers and visitors to our Site.

**_Information We Collect Directly From You_**. Certain areas and features of our Site require registration. To register you must provide your email address, first and last name, organization, phone number and other contact information. We also may collect additional optional information from you, including annual revenue, title, and supporter count. We may also collect information you submit to us on our Site, such as through “Contact Us” pages, or that you post to our Site (e.g., comments). Information we collect that identifies or is identifiable to a person is referred to in this Policy as “personal information.” 

**_Information We Collect Automatically_**. We may automatically collect the following information about your use of the Site through cookies, web beacons, log files, and other technologies: domain name; browser type and operating system; pages viewed, links clicked and other activities on the Site; IP address; the length of time using our Site; access time; device ID or other identifier; location and language information. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected, including where applicable, personal information. Please see the “Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” section below for more information.

#### **How We Use Your Information**

We use the information we collect, including personal information, for the following purposes:

  * To provide our Site and services, to communicate with customers and visitors, to respond to requests and inquiries, and for other customer service purposes
  * To tailor the content and information that we send or display, to offer location customization, and personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize experiences using the Site.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest them. We also may use the information that we collect to assist us in advertising our Site and our services on third party websites.
  * To better understand how users access and use our Site and services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site and services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.

#### **How We Share Your Information**

We may share the information we collect via the Site, including personal information, as follows:

  1. **_Affiliates.  _We may disclose the information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information will be subject to this Policy.**
  2. **_Third Parties.  _We may partner with third parties to make certain programs or offers available to you. If you elect to participate in such programs we may share certain of your information with these third parties. We do not share personal information with third parties for their direct marketing use.**
  3. ****_Service Providers.  _****We may disclose the information we collect from you to third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf.
  4. **_Business Transfers._  If we are acquired by or merged with another business, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another business, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other business.**
  5. **_In Response to Legal Process.  _We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena.**
  6. ****_To Protect Us and Others.  _****We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which Salsa Labs is involved.
  7. **_Aggregate and De-Identified Information.  _We may share aggregate or de-identified information about Customers and Supporters with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes.**

#### **Privacy Shield**

For information about our compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks, please see our Privacy Shield Privacy Policy.

#### **Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms**

We and our third party service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about the use of our Site. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect (and our third party service providers may do so on our behalf). 

**_Do Not Track_**. Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies), and opt out of certain ad networks. 

**_Cookies_**. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track activities on our Site. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Certain features of the Site will not function if you disable cookies.

**_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies_**. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track activities on the Site, help us manage content, and compile statistics about usage of the Site. We and our third party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML e-mails to our Customers, to help us track e-mail response rates, identify when our e-mails are viewed, and track whether our e-mails are forwarded.

**_Third Party Analytics_**. We use automated devices and applications on the Site, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site and, including our mobile application. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Site. We use these tools to help us improve our Site and services, performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services.

**_Targeted Advertising and Ad Networks_**. We may use third party services, such as Google AdWords, to send users targeted ads, based on their visit to our Site. We may also participate in third-party ad networks and allow third parties to use cookies, pixel tags and other tracking technologies on our Site to display targeted ads. These third parties may use cookies and other technologies to track your activities and display ads to you; they also may be able to associate the information they collect with other information they have about you from other sources. For information about Google AdWords, including how to opt out, visit Google’s Ads Settings page. You may also opt-out of many third-party ad networks, including those operated by members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). For more information regarding this practice by NAI members and DAA members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including how to opt-out of third-party ad networks operated by NAI and DAA members, please visit their respective websites: [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) (NAI); and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (DAA).

#### **User Generated Content**

We invite you to post content on our Site, including your comments, pictures, and any other information that you would like to be available on our Site. If you post content to our Site, all of the information that you post will be available to all visitors to our Site. If you post your own content on our Site, your posting may become public and the Company cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy.

#### **Third-Party Sites**

Our Site may contain links to, or appear on third-party websites. Any access to and use of such third party websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third party websites, and we are not responsible for the information practices of such third party websites.

#### **Security of Personal Information**

We have implemented precautions to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your information, password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

#### **Access to Personal Information**

You may modify your registration information by emailing us at [feedback@salsalabs.com](mailto:feedback@salsalabs.com). Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted will remain in our systems.

#### **Additional Terms for EU Visitors**

Salsa Labs processes personal data as both a “processor” and as a “controller” under the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation. We process personal data as a processor when providing the Salsa Platform to our customers, who may then make it available for access and use to their supporters. We act as a controller when we process the personal data you provide to us through the Site. This Section applies to our processing of personal data collected via the Site as a controller. To contact Salsa Labs about your personal data, see the section entitled “Contact Us,” below. 

We process personal data to pursue Salsa Lab’s legitimate business interests. To learn more about the purposes, legal basis and legitimate interests of Salsa Labs in processing your personal information, please see the section entitled “How We Use Your Information,” above. To learn with whom we share your personal information, please see the section entitled “How We Share Your Information,” above.

Please be aware that we may transfer your personal data to the United States where our servers are located. We will only transfer your personal information to the United States through the use of appropriate safeguards. Salsa Labs will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations. For users with a registered account on the Site, Salsa Labs will retain the information provided by you for as long as you have an account on the Site

You have the right to access your personal information, rectify inaccurate personal information kept about you, request the erasure of personal information that is no longer necessary for the purposes for which we have collected or processed the information, and to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances, for example if you are contesting the accuracy of the data. If you wish to access your personal information, please contact Salsa Labs through the contact listed below in writing and allow reasonable time for the data to be collected. You also have the right to receive personal information you have provided to us in a commonly used and machine-readable format and to transmit that personal information to any controller without hindrance from us. Finally, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

#### **Marketing Choices**

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to customers and prospective customers. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in any such e-mail. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you e-mails about your account or any services you have requested or received from us.

#### **Children Under 13**

Our Sites are not designed for children under 13. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our systems.

#### **Contact Us**

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Site or would like to make a complaint, please contact us at [feedback@salsalabs.com](mailto:feedback@salsalabs.com).

#### **Changes to this Policy**

This Policy is current as of the Effective Date set forth above. We may change this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes to this Policy here. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected, we will endeavor to provide notice in advance of such change by highlighting the change on our Site, or by emailing Customers or notifying them in another manner (e.g., such as when they log in to the Platform).
